<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<resources>
  <task name="hama">
    <!-- Hamilton Rating Scale for Anxiety (HAM-A) -->

    <string name="q1_title">HAM-A: 1. Anxious mood </string>
    <string name="q1_s">Q1 (anxious mood):</string>
    <string name="q1_question">This item covers the emotional condition of uncertainty about the future, ranging from worry, insecurity, irritability and apprehension to overpowering dread.</string>
    <string name="q1_option0">0 – The patient is neither more or less insecure or irritable than usual.</string>
    <string name="q1_option1">1 – Doubtful whether the patient is more insecure or irritable than usual.</string>
    <string name="q1_option2">2 – The patient expresses more clearly to be in a state of anxiety, apprehension or irritability, which he may find difficult to control. However, the worrying still is about minor matters and thus without influence on the patient’s daily life.</string>
    <string name="q1_option3">3 – At times the anxiety or insecurity is more difficult to control because the worrying is about major injuries or harms which might occur in the future. Has occasionally interfered with the patient’s daily life.</string>
    <string name="q1_option4">4 – The feeling of dread is present so often that it markedly interferes with the patient’s daily life.</string>
    <string name="q2_title">HAM-A: 2. Tension</string>
    <string name="q2_s">Q2 (tension):</string>
    <string name="q2_question">This item includes inability to relax, nervousness, bodily tensions, trembling and restless fatigue.</string>
    <string name="q2_option0">0 – The patient is neither more nor less tense than usual.</string>
    <string name="q2_option1">1 – The patient seems somewhat more nervous and tense than usual.</string>
    <string name="q2_option2">2 – Patient expresses clearly unable to relax and full of inner unrest, which he finds difficult to control, but it is still without influence on the patient’s daily life.</string>
    <string name="q2_option3">3 – The inner unrest and nervousness is so intense or frequent that it occasionally interferes with the patient’s daily work.</string>
    <string name="q2_option4">4 – Tensions and unrest interfere with the patient’s life and work at all times.</string>
    <string name="q3_title">HAM-A: 3. Fears</string>
    <string name="q3_s">Q3 (fears):</string>
    <string name="q3_question">This item includes fear of being in a crowd, of animals, of being in public places, of being alone, of traffic, of strangers, of dark etc. It is important to note whether there has been more phobic anxiety during the present episode than usual.</string>
    <string name="q3_option0">0 – Not present.</string>
    <string name="q3_option1">1 – Doubtful whether present.</string>
    <string name="q3_option2">2 – The patient experiences phobic anxiety but is able to fight it.</string>
    <string name="q3_option3">3 – It is difficult to fight or overcome the phobic anxiety, which thus to some extent interferes with the patient’s daily life and work.</string>
    <string name="q3_option4">4 – The phobic anxiety clearly interferes with the patient’s daily life and work.</string>
    <string name="q4_title">HAM-A: 4. Insomnia</string>
    <string name="q4_s">Q4 (insomnia):</string>
    <string name="q4_question">This item covers the patient’s subjective experience of sleep duration and sleep depth during the three preceding nights. Note: Administration of hypnotics or sedatives is disregarded.</string>
    <string name="q4_option0">0 – Usual sleep duration and sleep depth.</string>
    <string name="q4_option1">1 – Sleep duration is doubtfully or slightly reduced (e.g. due to difficulties falling asleep), but no change in sleep depth.</string>
    <string name="q4_option2">2 – Sleep depth is also reduced, sleep being more superficial. Sleep as a whole is somewhat disturbed.</string>
    <string name="q4_option3">3 – Sleep duration and sleep depth is markedly changed. Sleep periods total only a few hours per 24 hours.</string>
    <string name="q4_option4">4 – Sleep depth is so shallow that the patient speaks of short periods of slumber or dozing, but no real sleep.</string>
    <string name="q5_title">HAM-A: 5. Difficulties in concentration and memory</string>
    <string name="q5_s">Q5 (concentration/memory):</string>
    <string name="q5_question">This item covers difficulties in concentration, making decision about everyday matters, and memory.</string>
    <string name="q5_option0">0 – The patient has neither more nor less difficulty in concentration and/or memory that usual.</string>
    <string name="q5_option1">1 – Doubtful whether the patient has difficulty in concentration and/or memory.</string>
    <string name="q5_option2">2 – Even with a major effort it is difficult for the patient to concentrate on his daily routine work.</string>
    <string name="q5_option3">3 – The patient has pronounced difficulties with concentration, memory, or decision making, e.g. in reading a newspaper article or watching a television programme to the end.</string>
    <string name="q5_option4">4 – During the interview the patient shows difficulty in concentration, memory or decision making.</string>
    <string name="q6_title">HAM-A: 6. Depressed mood </string>
    <string name="q6_s">Q6 (depressed mood):</string>
    <string name="q6_question">This item covers both the verbal and the non-verbal communication of sadness, depression, despondency, helplessness and hopelessness.</string>
    <string name="q6_option0">0 – Not present.</string>
    <string name="q6_option1">1 – Doubtful whether the patient is more despondent or sad than usual, or is only vaguely so.</string>
    <string name="q6_option2">2 – The patient is more clearly concerned with unpleasant experiences, although he still lacks helplessness or hopelessness.</string>
    <string name="q6_option3">3 – The patient shows clear non-verbal signs of depression and/or hopelessness.</string>
    <string name="q6_option4">4 – The patient remarks on despondency and helplessness or the non-verbal signs dominate the interview and the patient cannot be distracted.</string>
    <string name="q7_title">HAM-A: 7. General somatic symptoms: Muscular</string>
    <string name="q7_s">Q7 (somatic, muscular):</string>
    <string name="q7_question">Weakness, stiffness, soreness or real pain, more or less diffusely localized in the muscles, such as jaw ache or neck ache.</string>
    <string name="q7_option0">0 – The patient is neither more nor less sore or stiff in the muscles than usual.</string>
    <string name="q7_option1">1 – The patient seems somewhat more stiff or sore in the muscles than usual.</string>
    <string name="q7_option2">2 – The symptoms have the character of pain.</string>
    <string name="q7_option3">3 – Muscle pain interferes to some extent with the patient’s daily work and life.</string>
    <string name="q7_option4">4 – Muscle pain is present most of the time and clearly interferes with the patient’s daily work and life.</string>
    <string name="q8_title">HAM-A: 8. General somatic symptoms: Sensory </string>
    <string name="q8_s">Q8 (somatic, sensory):</string>
    <string name="q8_question">This item includes increased fatigability and weakness or real functional disturbances of the senses, including tinnitus, blurring of vision, hot and cold flashes and prickling sensations.</string>
    <string name="q8_option0">0 – Not present.</string>
    <string name="q8_option1">1 – Doubtful whether the patient’s indications of symptoms are more pronounced than usual.</string>
    <string name="q8_option2">2 – The sensations of pressure reach the character of buzzing in the ears, visual disturbances and prickling or itching sensations in the skin.</string>
    <string name="q8_option3">3 – The generalized sensory symptoms interfere to some extent with the patient’s daily life and work.</string>
    <string name="q8_option4">4 – The generalized sensory symptoms are present most of the time and clearly interfere with the patient’s daily life and work.</string>
    <string name="q9_title">HAM-A: 9. Cardiovascular symptoms</string>
    <string name="q9_s">Q9 (cardiovascular):</string>
    <string name="q9_question">This item includes tachycardia, palpitations, oppression, chest pain, throbbing in the blood vessels, and feelings of faintness.</string>
    <string name="q9_option0">0 – Not present.</string>
    <string name="q9_option1">1 – Doubtful whether present.</string>
    <string name="q9_option2">2 – Cardiovascular symptoms are present, but the patient can still control them.</string>
    <string name="q9_option3">3 – The patient has occasional difficulty controlling the cardiovascular symptoms, which thus to some extent interfere with his daily life and work.</string>
    <string name="q9_option4">4 – Cardiovascular symptoms are present most of the time and clearly interfere with the patient’s daily life and work.</string>
    <string name="q10_title">HAM-A: 10. Respiratory symptoms</string>
    <string name="q10_s">Q10 (respiratory):</string>
    <string name="q10_question">Feelings of constriction or contraction in throat or chest, dyspnoea or choking sensations and sighing respiration.</string>
    <string name="q10_option0">0 – Not present.</string>
    <string name="q10_option1">1 – Doubtful whether present.</string>
    <string name="q10_option2">2 – Respiratory symptoms are present, but the patient can still control them.</string>
    <string name="q10_option3">3 – The patient has occasional difficulty controlling the respiratory symptoms, which thus to some extent interfere with his daily life and work.</string>
    <string name="q10_option4">4 – Respiratory symptoms are present most of the time and clearly interfere with the patient’s daily life and work.</string>
    <string name="q11_title">HAM-A: 11. Gastro-intestinal symptoms</string>
    <string name="q11_s">Q11 (gastrointestinal):</string>
    <string name="q11_question">This item covers difficulties in swallowing, “sinking” sensation in stomach, dyspepsia (heartburn or burning sensation in the stomach, abdominal pains related to meals, fullness, nausea and vomiting), abdominal rumbling and diarrhoea.</string>
    <string name="q11_option0">0 – Not present.</string>
    <string name="q11_option1">1 – Doubtful whether present (or doubtful whether different from usual).</string>
    <string name="q11_option2">2 – One or more gastro-intestinal symptoms are present, but the patient can still control them.</string>
    <string name="q11_option3">3 – The patient has occasional difficulty controlling the gastro-intestinal symptoms, which to some extent interfere with his daily life and work.</string>
    <string name="q11_option4">4 – The gastro-intestinal symptoms are present most of the time and interfere clearly with the patient’s daily life and work.</string>
    <string name="q12_title">HAM-A: 12. Genito-urinary symptoms </string>
    <string name="q12_s">Q12 (genitourinary):</string>
    <string name="q12_question">This item includes non-organic or psychic symptoms such as frequent or more pressing passing of urine, menstrual irregularities, anorgasmia, dyspareunia, premature ejaculation, loss of erection.</string>
    <string name="q12_option0">0 – Not present.</string>
    <string name="q12_option1">1 – Doubtful whether present (or doubtful whether different from usual).</string>
    <string name="q12_option2">2 – One or more genito-urinary symptoms are present, but do not interfere with the patient’s daily life and work.</string>
    <string name="q12_option3">3 – Occasionally, one or more genito-urinary symptoms are present to such a degree that they interfere to some extent with the patient’s daily life and work.</string>
    <string name="q12_option4">4 – The genito-urinary symptoms are present most of the time and interfere clearly with the patient’s daily life and work.</string>
    <string name="q13_title">HAM-A: 13. Other autonomic symptoms</string>
    <string name="q13_s">Q13 (other autonomic):</string>
    <string name="q13_question">This item includes dryness of the mouth, blushing or pallor, sweating and dizziness.</string>
    <string name="q13_option0">0 – Not present.</string>
    <string name="q13_option1">1 – Doubtful whether present.</string>
    <string name="q13_option2">2 – One or more autonomic symptoms are present, but they do not interfere with the patient’s daily life and work.</string>
    <string name="q13_option3">3 – Occasionally, one or more autonomic symptoms are present to such a degree that they interfere to some extent with the patient’s daily life and work.</string>
    <string name="q13_option4">4 – Autonomic symptoms are present most of the time and clearly interfere with the patient’s daily life and work.</string>
    <string name="q14_title">HAM-A: 14. Behaviour during interview</string>
    <string name="q14_s">Q14 (behaviour in interview):</string>
    <string name="q14_question">The patient may appear tense, nervous, agitated, restless, tremulous, pale, hyperventilating or sweating during the interview. Based on such observations a global estimate is made.</string>
    <string name="q14_option0">0 – The patient does not appear anxious.</string>
    <string name="q14_option1">1 – It is doubtful whether the patient is anxious.</string>
    <string name="q14_option2">2 – The patient is moderately anxious.</string>
    <string name="q14_option3">3 – The patient is markedly anxious.</string>
    <string name="q14_option4">4 – Patient is overwhelmed by anxiety, for example with shaking and trembling all over.</string>
    <string name="symptom_severity">HAM-A symptom severity</string>

  </task>
</resources>
