<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<resources>
  <task name="icd10specpd">
    <!-- ICD-10 criteria for specific personality disorders (F60) -->

<!--
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
ICD-10 criteria
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
Copyright © 1992 World Health Organization
- The ICD-10 Classification of Mental and Behavioural Disorders:
  Clinical descriptions and diagnostic guidelines (CDDG).
  http://www.who.int/entity/classifications/icd/en/bluebook.pdf
  Accessed 2013-05-08.
- The ICD-10 Classification of Mental and Behavioural Disorders:
  Diagnostic Criteria for Research (DCR-10).
  http://www.who.int/classifications/icd/en/GRNBOOK.pdf
  Accessed 2013-05-08.

Used here with permission:

“On behalf of the World Health Organization, we are pleased to authorize
your request to reproduce the WHO material as detailed in the form below.
    This permission is subject to the following conditions:
- This is a non-exclusive permission to reproduce the material detailed below.
- Please ensure that the original WHO source is appropriately acknowledged
with the appropriate bibliographical reference including publication title,
author, publisher, volume/edition number, page numbers, copyright notice year
and the URL reference and the date accessed.
- The material will be reproduced as it was published by WHO and no changes
should be made to the content or meaning.
Publishers may reformat the material in the style of the publication.
- The use of WHO materials should be factual and used in an appropriate context;
- The material should not be reproduced for use in association with product
marketing or promotional activities.
- The copyright in ICD-10 is vested in WHO, any further redistribution of
the text requires permission from WHO.
- There should be no suggestion that WHO endorses any specific company or
products in the article, book etc or in the manner of distribution of the
article, book etc.
- The WHO logo and emblem shall not be reproduced.
- WHO reserves the right to withdraw the permission in the event a condition
is not respected.”
-->

    <string name="general">General criteria for personality disorders (F60)</string>
    <string name="G1">G1 [PATHOLOGICAL 1]. Evidence that the individual’s characteristic and enduring patterns of inner experience and behaviour deviate markedly as a whole from the culturally expected and accepted range (or ‘norm’).</string>
    <string name="G1b">Such deviation must be manifest in more than one of the following areas:</string>
    <string name="G1_1">(1) cognition (i.e. ways of perceiving and interpreting things, people and events; forming attitudes and images of self and others)</string>
    <string name="G1_2">(2) affectivity (range, intensity and appropriateness of emotional arousal and response)</string>
    <string name="G1_3">(3) control over impulses and need gratification</string>
    <string name="G1_4">(4) relating to others and manner of handling interpersonal situations</string>
    <string name="G2">G2 [PERVASIVE]. The deviation must manifest itself pervasively as behaviour that is inflexible, maladaptive, or otherwise dysfunctional across a broad range of personal and social situations (i.e. not being limited to one specific ‘triggering’ stimulus or situation).</string>
    <string name="G3">G3 [PATHOLOGICAL 2]. There is personal distress, or adverse impact on the social environment, or both, clearly attributable to the behaviour referred to under G2.</string>
    <string name="G4">G4 [PERSISTENT]. There must be evidence that the deviation is stable and of long duration, having its onset in late childhood or adolescence.</string>
    <string name="G5">G5 [PRIMARY 1]. The deviation cannot be explained as a manifestation or consequence of other adult mental disorders, although episodic or chronic conditions from sections F0 to F7 of this classification may co-exist, or be superimposed on it.</string>
    <string name="G6">G6 [PRIMARY 2]. Organic brain disease, injury, or dysfunction must be excluded as possible cause of the deviation (if such organic causation is demonstrable, use category F07).</string>
    <string name="comments">The assessment of G1 to G6 above should be based on as many sources of information as possible. Although sometimes it is possible to obtain sufficient evidence from a single interview with the subject, as a general rule it is recommended to have more than one interview with the person and to collect history data from informants or past records.</string>
    <string name="meets_general_criteria">Meets general criteria for personality disorder</string>
    <string name="general_criteria_must_be_met">A. The general criteria of personality disorder (F60) must be met.</string>
    <string name="skip_this_pd">Skip this personality disorder</string>
    <string name="paranoid_pd_title">F60.0 Paranoid personality disorder</string>
    <string name="paranoid_pd_B">B. At least four of the following must be present:</string>
    <string name="paranoid1">(1) Excessive sensitivity to setbacks and rebuffs.</string>
    <string name="paranoid2">(2) Tendency to bear grudges persistently, e.g. unforgiveness of insults, injuries or slights.</string>
    <string name="paranoid3">(3) Suspiciousness and a pervasive tendency to distort experience by misconstruing the neutral or friendly actions of others as hostile or contemptuous.</string>
    <string name="paranoid4">(4) A combative and tenacious sense of personal rights out of keeping with the actual situation.</string>
    <string name="paranoid5">(5) Recurrent suspicions, without justification, regarding sexual fidelity of spouse or sexual partner.</string>
    <string name="paranoid6">(6) Persistent self-referential attitude, associated particularly with excessive self-importance.</string>
    <string name="paranoid7">(7) Preoccupation with unsubstantiated “conspiratorial” explanations of events around the subject or in the world at large.</string>
    <string name="schizoid_pd_title">F60.1 Schizoid personality disorder</string>
    <string name="schizoid_pd_B">B. At least four of the following criteria must be present:</string>
    <string name="schizoid1">(1) Few, if any, activities provide pleasure.</string>
    <string name="schizoid2">(2) Displays emotional coldness, detachment, or flattened affectivity.</string>
    <string name="schizoid3">(3) Limited capacity to express warm, tender feelings for others as well as anger.</string>
    <string name="schizoid4">(4) Appears indifferent to either praise or criticism of others.</string>
    <string name="schizoid5">(5) Little interest in having sexual experiences with another person (taking into account age).</string>
    <string name="schizoid6">(6) Almost always chooses solitary activities.</string>
    <string name="schizoid7">(7) Excessive preoccupation with fantasy and introspection.</string>
    <string name="schizoid8">(8) Neither desires, nor has, any close friends or confiding relationships (or only one).</string>
    <string name="schizoid9">(9) Marked insensitivity to prevailing social norms and conventions; if these are not followed this is unintentional.</string>
    <string name="dissocial_pd_title">F60.2 Dissocial personality disorder</string>
    <string name="dissocial_pd_B">B. At least three of the following must be present:</string>
    <string name="dissocial1">(1) Callous unconcern for the feelings of others.</string>
    <string name="dissocial2">(2) Gross and persistent attitude of irresponsibility and disregard for social norms, rules, and obligations.</string>
    <string name="dissocial3">(3) Incapacity to maintain enduring relationships, though having no difficulty to establish them.</string>
    <string name="dissocial4">(4) Very low tolerance to frustration and a low threshold for discharge of aggression, including violence.</string>
    <string name="dissocial5">(5) Incapacity to experience guilt, or to profit from adverse experience, particularly punishment.</string>
    <string name="dissocial6">(6) Marked proneness to blame others, or to offer plausible rationalizations for the behaviour bringing the subject into conflict with society.</string>
    <string name="dissocial_pd_comments">Comments: Persistent irritability and the presence of conduct disorder during childhood and adolescence, complete the clinical picture but are not required for the diagnosis.</string>
    <string name="eu_pd_title">F60.3 Emotionally unstable personality disorder</string>
    <string name="eu_pd_i_title">F60.30 Emotionally unstable personality disorder, impulsive type</string>
    <string name="eu_pd_i_B">B. At least three of the following must be present, one of which is (2):</string>
    <string name="eu1">(1) A marked tendency to act unexpectedly and without consideration of the consequences.</string>
    <string name="eu2">(2) A marked tendency to quarrelsome behaviour and to conflicts with others, especially when impulsive acts are thwarted or criticized.</string>
    <string name="eu3">(3) Liability to outbursts of anger or violence, with inability to control the resulting behavioural explosions.</string>
    <string name="eu4">(4) Difficulty in maintaining any course of action that offers no immediate reward.</string>
    <string name="eu5">(5) Unstable and capricious mood.</string>
    <string name="eu_pd_b_title">F60.31 Emotionally unstable personality disorder, borderline type</string>
    <string name="eu_pd_b_B">B. At least three of the symptoms mentioned above in criterion B (F60.30) must be present, and in addition at least two of the following:</string>
    <string name="eu6">(6) Disturbances in and uncertainty about self-image, aims and internal preferences (including sexual).</string>
    <string name="eu7">(7) Liability to become involved in intense and unstable relationships, often leading to emotional crises.</string>
    <string name="eu8">(8) Excessive efforts to avoid abandonment.</string>
    <string name="eu9">(9) Recurrent threats or acts of self-harm.</string>
    <string name="eu10">(10) Chronic feelings of emptiness.</string>
    <string name="histrionic_pd_title">F60.4 Histrionic personality disorder</string>
    <string name="histrionic_pd_B">B. At least four of the following must be present:</string>
    <string name="histrionic1">(1) Self-dramatization, theatricality, or exaggerated expression of emotions.</string>
    <string name="histrionic2">(2) Suggestibility, easily influenced by others or by circumstances.</string>
    <string name="histrionic3">(3) Shallow and labile affectivity.</string>
    <string name="histrionic4">(4) Continually seeks excitement and activities in which the subject is the centre of attention.</string>
    <string name="histrionic5">(5) Inappropriately seductive in appearance or behaviour.</string>
    <string name="histrionic6">(6) Overly concerned with physical attractiveness.</string>
    <string name="histrionic_pd_comments">Comments: Egocentricity, self-indulgence, continuous longing for appreciation, lack of consideration for others, feelings that are easily hurt, and persistent manipulative behaviour complete the clinical picture, but are not required for the diagnosis.</string>
    <string name="anankastic_pd_title">F60.5 Anankastic personality disorder</string>
    <string name="anankastic_pd_note">Note: Often referred to as obsessive-compulsive personality disorder.</string>
    <string name="anankastic_pd_B">B. At least four of the following must be present:</string>
    <string name="anankastic1">(1) Feelings of excessive doubt and caution.</string>
    <string name="anankastic2">(2) Preoccupation with details, rules, lists, order, organization or schedule.</string>
    <string name="anankastic3">(3) Perfectionism that interferes with task completion.</string>
    <string name="anankastic4">(4) Excessive conscientiousness and scrupulousness.</string>
    <string name="anankastic5">(5) Undue preoccupation with productivity to the exclusion of pleasure and interpersonal relationships.</string>
    <string name="anankastic6">(6) Excessive pedantry and adherence to social conventions.</string>
    <string name="anankastic7">(7) Rigidity and stubbornness.</string>
    <string name="anankastic8">(8) Unreasonable insistence that others submit to exactly his or her way of doing things, or unreasonable reluctance to allow others to do things.</string>
    <string name="anxious_pd_title">F60.6 Anxious [avoidant] personality disorder</string>
    <string name="anxious_pd_B">B. At least four of the following must be present:</string>
    <string name="anxious1">(1) Persistent and pervasive feelings of tension and apprehension.</string>
    <string name="anxious2">(3) Excessive preoccupation about being criticized or rejected in social situations.</string>
    <string name="anxious3">(4) Unwillingness to get involved with people unless certain of being liked.</string>
    <string name="anxious4">(5) Restrictions in lifestyle because of need of security.</string>
    <string name="anxious5">(6) Avoidance of social or occupational activities that involve significant interpersonal contact, because of fear of criticism, disapproval or rejection.</string>
    <string name="dependent_pd_title">F60.7 Dependent personality disorder</string>
    <string name="dependent_pd_B">B. At least four of the following must be present:</string>
    <string name="dependent1">(1) Encouraging or allowing others to make most of one’s important life decisions.</string>
    <string name="dependent2">(2) Subordination of one’s own needs to those of others on whom one is dependent, and undue compliance with their wishes.</string>
    <string name="dependent3">(3) Unwillingness to make even reasonable demands on the people one depends on.</string>
    <string name="dependent4">(4) Feeling uncomfortable or helpless when alone, because of exaggerated fears of inability to care for oneself.</string>
    <string name="dependent5">(5) Preoccupation with fears of being left to take care of oneself.</string>
    <string name="dependent6">(6) Limited capacity to make everyday decisions without an excessive amount of advice and reassurance from others.</string>
    <string name="other_pd_title">F60.8 Other specified personality disorders</string>
    <string name="other_pd_comments">If none of the preceding rubrics is fitting, but a condition meeting the general criteria for personality disorder listed under F60 is nevertheless present, use this code. An extra character may be added for identifying specific personality disorders not currently in ICD-10. In using code F60.8, it is recommended always to record a vignette description of the specific disorder.</string>
    <string name="vignette">Vignette:</string>

  </task>
</resources>
