<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<resources>
  <task name="paradise24">

<!--
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
PARADISE 24
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~

Copyright © 2015 Cieza et al.

"This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative
Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and
reproduction in any medium, provided the original author and source are
properly credited."

- Cieza A, Sabariego C, Anczewska M, Ballert C, Bickenbach J, Cabello M,
  Giovannetti A, Kaskela T, Mellor B, Pitkänen T, Quintas R, Raggi A, Świtaj P,
  Chatterji S; PARADISE Consortium (2015).
  PARADISE 24: A Measure to Assess the Impact of Brain Disorders on People's
  Lives.
  *PLoS One* 10: e0132410.
  https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/26147343;
  article https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0132410;
  Supplementary File 1 https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0132410.s001;
  Supplementary File 2 https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0132410.s002.

-->

    <string name="title">PARADISE 24</string>
    <string name="instructions">The following questions address problems and difficulties you might have in different functions of your body and areas of your life. Please, answer them thinking back over the <b>past 30 days</b> and <b>taking both good and bad days into account.</b></string>

    <string name="q1">How much of a problem did you have due to <b>not feeling rested and refreshed</b> during the day (e.g. feeling tired, not having energy)?</string>
    <string name="q2">How much of a problem did you have with <b>loss of interest</b>?</string>
    <string name="q3">How much of a problem did you have with your <b>appetite</b>?</string>
    <string name="q4">How much of a problem did you have with <b>sleeping</b>, such as falling asleep, waking up frequently during the night or waking up too early in the morning?</string>
    <string name="q5">How much of a problem did you have <b>being so irritable</b> that you started arguments, shouted at people or even hit people?</string>
    <string name="q6">How much of a problem did you have with being <b>slowed down</b> or feeling as if <b>things were moving too fast</b> around you?</string>
    <string name="q7">How much of a problem did you have with <b>feeling sad, low or depressed</b>?</string>
    <string name="q8">How much of a problem did you have with <b>worry or anxiety</b>?</string>
    <string name="q9">How much of a problem did you have with <b>not being able to cope with all the things</b> that you had to do?</string>
    <string name="q10">How much <b>bodily ache or pain</b> did you have?</string>
    <string name="q11">How much difficulty did you have in <b>concentrating on doing something for ten minutes</b>?</string>
    <string name="q12">How much difficulty did you have in <b>remembering to do important things</b>?</string>
    <string name="q13">How much difficulty did you have in <b>making decisions</b>?</string>
    <string name="q14">How much difficulty did you have in <b>starting and maintaining a conversation</b>?</string>
    <string name="q15">How much difficulty did you have in <b>walking a long distance</b> such as a kilometre (or equivalent)?</string>
    <string name="q16">How much difficulty did you have in <b>grooming or dressing, toileting or eating</b>?</string>
    <string name="q17">How much difficulty did you have in <b>sexual activities</b>?</string>
    <string name="q18">How much difficulty did you have in <b>staying by yourself for a few days</b>?</string>
    <string name="q19">How much difficulty did you have with <b>looking after your health</b>, such as eating well, exercising and taking your medicines?</string>
    <string name="q20">How much difficulty did you have in <b>initiating and maintaining a friendship</b>?</string>
    <string name="q21">How much difficulty did you have in <b>getting along with people who are close to you</b>?</string>
    <string name="q22">How much difficulty did you have in your <b>day-to-day work or school</b>?</string>
    <string name="q23">How much difficulty did you have with <b>managing your money</b>?</string>
    <string name="q24">How much difficulty did you have in <b>joining in community activities</b> (for example, festivities, religious or other activities) in the same way as anyone else can?</string>

    <!--
        "Row score" is likely a typo for "raw score", as in the paper.
        <string name="sum_per_column">Sum row score per column</string>
        <string name="total_row_score">Total row score</string>
    -->
    <string name="raw_score">Raw score</string>  <!-- added; this is the phrasing in the paper -->
    <string name="metric_score">Metric score</string>

    <string name="option_0">None</string>
    <string name="option_1">Some</string>
    <string name="option_2">A lot</string>
  </task>
</resources>
